

Personal information

Surname / First name

Ziosi Brunetto Marco

Address

via Ivancich n.17, 30174, Chirignago (VE)

Telephone

Nationality

(+39) 3474958152

Email

brunetto.ziosi@gmail.com

brunettomarco.ziosi@studenti.unipd.it

Italian

Date of birth

03/05/1985

Current Position

PhD student since 01/2012 at Università degli Studi di Padova - Dipartimento di Fisica e Astronomia **PhD advisors:** Dr. Michela Mapelli (INAF-OAPd) and Prof. Giuseppe Tormen (University of Padova) **PhD Fellowship funded by:** Strategic Research Project AACSE - Algorithms and Architectures for Computational Science and Engineering

Education

2012-present

PhD School in Astronomy - Dipartimento di Fisica e Astronomia (Università degli Studi di Padova), Research project title: "The impact of stellar evolution and dynamics on the formation of compact-object binaries", supervisors: Dr. Michela Mapelli and Prof. Giuseppe Tormen

2007-2011

Master Degree Thesis in Astronomy - Dipartimento di Fisica e Astronomia (Università degli Studi di Padova), (108/110): "Halo-matter cross-correlation in cosmological simulation", supervisors: Prof. Giuseppe Tormen and Prof. Ravi K. Sheth

2004-2007

Bachelor Degree Thesis in Astronomy - Dipartimento di Fisica e Astronomia (Università degli Studi di Padova), (103/110): "Studio del profilo dei vortici ottici con diverso momento angolare" (Characterization of optical vortexes with different angular momentum), supervisors: Prof. Cesare Barbieri, Dr. Fabrizio Tamburini, Dr. Gabriele Anzolin

Teaching experience

2012-2013

Teaching assistant - Dipartimento di Fisica e Astronomia (Università degli Studi di Padova), Mathematical analysis

2012-2013

Teaching assistant - Dipartimento di Fisica e Astronomia (Università degli Studi di Padova), Python course

Grants

2013

1000 EUR to attend the Gravasco IHP trimester "N-body gravitational dynamical systems From N=2 to infinity..."

Accepted computational proposals

2014

"Star cluster formation through merger of sub-clusters", 50.0k CPU hours on IBM PLX cluster @ CINECA, PI: Mapelli, CO-I: Ziosi and 3 other COIs

2013

"Investigating the statistics and parameter space of double compact object binaries in young star clusters", 50.0k CPU hours on GPU cluster EURORA, IBM PLX cluster and IBM Blue Gene/Q Fermi @ CINECA, PI: Ziosi, 2 COIs

2013

"Making very massive stars through stellar collisions", 50.0k on GPU cluster EURORA and IBM PLX cluster @ CINECA, PI: Mapelli, CO-I: Ziosi and 2 other COIs

2012

"The violent life of the Galactic Centre", 281.6k CPU hours on IBM PLX and on the IBM Blue Gene/Q Fermi cluster @ CINECA, PI: Mapelli, CO-I: Ziosi and 2 other COIs

2012

"Computational Frontiers of Black Hole Dynamics", 50.0k CPU hours on IBM PLX cluster @ CINECA, PI: Ripamonti, CO-I: Ziosi and 2 other COIs

Schools and Workshops

2014

- Perspectives of GPU computing in Physics and Astrophysics, Dep. of Physics of Sapienza -Rome, 15-17 Semptember 2014 (poster)
- Stellar N-body Dynamics, Sexten (Italy), 8-12 September 2014 (poster)
- Astro-GR@Rome, Monteporzio Catone (Rome), 14-18 July 2014
- MODEST 14 The dance of stars: dense stellar systems from infant to old, Bad Honnef Physics Center (Germany), 2-6 June 2014 (poster)

2013

- Workshop on Dynamics & Kinetic theory of self-gravitating systems, Gravasco IHP trimester "N-body gravitational dynamical systems From N=2 to infinity...", Paris, 4-8 November 2013 (contributed talk)
- Seminar on Galactic Dynamics, Gravasco IHP trimester "N body gravitational dynamical systems From N=2 to infinity...", Paris, 21 October-1 November 2013
- Workshop on High Performance Scientific Computing, Strategic Research Project AACSE,
 Departement of Information Engineering Padova, 9 Semptember 2013
- PhD Summer School on High Performance Scientific Computing, Strategic Research Project AACSE, Departement of Information Engineering - Padua, 16-18 Semptember 2013 (contributed talk)
- INFN School Of Statistics, Vietri sul Mare (Italy), 3-7 June 2013
- School on Gravitational Waves, neutrinos and multiwavelenght e.m. observations: the new frontier of Astronomy, Monteporzio Catone (Rome), 10-15 April 2013

2012

- IMPRS Summer School on Computational Astrophysics, Heidelberg, Germany, 10-14
 September 2012
- International School of Astrophysics on the Fundamental Cosmic distance scale and the Transient Sky, Teramo, Italy, 11-15 June 2012 (contributed talk)
- Summer School of Parallel Computing, CINECA (Bologna), 2-13 July 2012
- Introduction to C language for scientific programming, CINECA (Bologna), 17-18 May 2012

2011

- PhD Summer School on Algorithms and Architectures for Computational Science and Engineering, Departement of Information Engineering - Padua, 12-16 Semptember 2011 (contributed talk)
- Workshop on Visualization of Large scientific Data, CINECA (Bologna), 14-15 June 2011
- Python for computational science, CINECA, 16-18 May 2011
- Introduction to GPGPU and CUDA programming, CINECA (Bologna), 27 April 2011

Publications

- Ziosi B. M., Mapelli M., Branchesi M., Tormen G., 2014, MNRAS, 441, 3703Z
- Branchesi M. et al., C7 multi-messenger astronomy of GW sources, 2014, General Relativity and Gravitation, 46, 1771

Language skills

Italian (Mother tongue), English (good)

Computer skills

OSs

Scripting/Programming Languages

Data Analysis/Plotting tools

Markup Languages/Web

Graphics

Presentation

Office/Internet

Others

Signature

Linux (expert), MacOSX (advanced), Windows (advanced)

Python (advanced), Go (good), Bash (good), C/C++ (good), Matlab/Octave (good), Fortran (base), IDL (base)

Veusz (good), Matplotlib/Pylab (advanced), Supermongo (base), Gnuplot (base), IDL (base), IRAF (base)

LaTeX (expert), HTML (base), Javascript (base)

Inkscape (good), Gimp (good), ImageMagick (good), Blender (base)

Beamer, Sozi/Inkscape, Prezi, PowerPoint

MSOffice, LibreOffice/OpenOffice, Chrome, Internet Explorer, Firefox, Opera, Outlook, Thuderbird Git (good), MySQL (base)

Bruits how Dia.